shiltonjack@gmail.com LinkedIn — GitHub +447946768302

ABOUT ME

I am a reliable, focused, and confident individual, with experience in successful self-guided study, which includes learning the Japanese language. I enjoy problem solving, which has included the utilisation of Linux, Git, database design, and querying. Having volunteered as a software developer for various companies I have experience in many languages, such as Java, C#, and Python.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, C#, HTML, SQL, Python, JavaScript

Languages: English, Japanese (N5)

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham

BSc Computer Science w/ Year Abroad Currently Enrolled

Student

Special Events Officer of Computer Science Society (Jun. 2021 – Ongoing)

Member of Computer Science Society (Sep. 2020 – Ongoing)

Member of AFNOM (Ethical Hacking Society) (Sep. 2020 – Ongoing)

Member of Japan Society (Sep. 2020 – Ongoing)

Hereford Sixth Form College

A-Level

A-Levels in Computer Science (A*), Maths (A), Physics (B), and Extended Project (A)

Graduated July. 2020

Extended Project Qualification: Japanese Culture (Jun 2019 – Jul 2020)

Teaching Aide (A-Level Computer Science) (Dec 2019 – Jul 2020)

Queen Elizabeth Humanities College

11 GCSE Grades: Ranging from 5-9

Graduated July. 2018

GCSE Mathematics (Grade 9)

GCSE Physics (Grade 7)

GCSE Information Technology (A Grade)

EXPERIENCE

Student

Developer Club Lead

Birmingham, UK

July 2021 - Present

Google

Public Speaking: Presenting workshops to students, focusing on topics of Computer Science and the process of developing applications.

Communication: Leading a team of presenters in producing, executing, and evaluating workshops over the course of the University year.

Leadership: Acting as the representative of the Google Developer Student Club at the University of Birmingham, ensuring that the team I lead can work effectively and collaboratively together.

Special Events Officer

Birmingham, UK

Computer Science Society - University of Birmingham

April 2021 - Present

Team Management: Leading and organising a team in the process of planning, execution, and debrief of larger events hosted by the society.

Problem Solving: Working with a team to solve issues that arise during the creation and delivery of events held by

Public Figure: Acting as the face of the society as a committee member, ensuring that members feel safe and comfortable in the environment created.

Sales Assistant Hereford, UK

Cex Nov 2019 - July 2021

Diagnostic Tester: Testing equipment functionality on a large range of devices, and subsequently repairing, if possible.

Budget Management: Accessing current wage spend, stock levels, and sales in order to make appropriate adjustments to boost sales.

Customer Management: Working as part of a team to develop skills in order to secure sales and improve customer service, on occasion diffusing potentially hostile situations, while also working to maximise customer satisfaction.

Guest Speaker Hereford, UK

Hereford Sixth Form College

June 2021.

Public Presentation: Recently invited back to Hereford Sixth Form to speak to current students via a presentation, on the subject of the University I am attending, my process of picking a university, and why I chose to study Computer Science.

Teaching Assistant Placement - Computer Science

Worcester, UK

Worcester Sixth Form College

July 2017.

Course Development: Produced a course for students studying at the Sixth Form, focused on 3D Modelling using Blender, an industry standard software.

Teaching: Taught students attending the Sixth Form basics about database management and simple SQL.

PROJECTS

Inky Finance Birmingham

Python, Pandas, Git, IntelliJ

July 2021 - Present

Description: Inky Finance is a startup company focused on creating a decentralised algorithmic trading platform, which will allow its users to easily create marketing strategies when buying or selling stocks. It uses pandas to import and process big data of current stock values in order to create an effect strategy.

jack-development.github.io

Website

HTML, Sass, JavaScript, React, Git, IntelliJ

June 2021 - Present

Description: A website developed with the goal of creating an online presence for me to supply to clients, colleagues, or potential employers. It also served as an introduction into using React alongside GitHub pages and deploying website builds from React.

Jabber

University of Birmingham

Java, SQL, SceneBuilder, Git, JavaFX, IntelliJ

10th - 16th May 2021

Description: "Jabber" was a mock social network platform where teams were tasked with creating a front and back end service for the social network. We were given a basic database containing information on clients and messages that we would need to query in a secure fashion and present to the end user.

Super Mario Bros. 1985

Hereford Sixth Form College

C#, Windows Forms, Visual Studio, .csv, Excel

June 2019 - July 2020

Description: A Windows Form project that utilised Visual Studio development, I recreated the 1985 original version of Super Mario Bros. The program used a lookup sheet alongside a .csv file, edited using Excel, in order to create a level design system that allowed a massive diversity in level creation and subsequently custom level design, this was the beginning of a simple database system.

For this project I produced a paper that focused on the planning, development, and testing of the product, all the way through from conception to a theoretical release.

This project is now planned to be used as an exemplar for students at the Sixth Form.

Links: Paper

Gyration Hop Mobile App

C#, Unity, Google Play Console, Xcode, CAD

May 2018 - Oct 2020

Description: A competitive infinite runner game that I developed for Android devices, focused on building the skills of hand-eye coordination for the users. This was developed in Unity and was eventually pushed to Apple devices as well, by request of beta testers. The game gained attention from the newspaper, the Hereford Times, which wrote an article around it.

Platforms: Google Play, Apple App Store

Link: Google Play Store